Andrey Fedorovich

Frontend developer - Gomel, Belarus

+375 29 828 99 07 a.fedorovich@protonmail.com

About

Web developer with over 3 years of experience

Participated in the development of browser extensions, desktop applications, websites, e-mails and PDF documents

Strong knowledge about UI development (accessibility, semantic, optimization)

Understanding OOP, Design Pattern

Experience with build systems (e.g Webpack, Gulp)

I enjoy learning and helping others to learn new things

Technologies and Tools



Work Experience

Frontend Developer at Epam Systems Belarus, Minsk Jun 2020 - Present 4 months

Javascript Developer at PixelPlex Belarus, Minsk Feb 2018 - Jun 2020 almost 3 years

UI developer at DShop24
Belarus, Minsk
Feb 2016 - Nov 2016 9 months

Projects

Mars

Role: Frontend developer at Epam Systems

Description: Extending platform capability from Starter Kit project to include new

components, variations of existing components, interactive tools, and

themes.

Technologies: React, Jest, TypeScript, Storybook

Tools: VS Code, Azure Dev Tools, Teams, Zeplin

FLAK

Role: Frontend developer at PixelPlex

Description: The application for managing the processes of voting for resolutions.

There are has two roles Cosecrotary and Cosignatory in the project. Cosecrotary can create resolutions for the company, invite Cosignatory, add companies to the system. A Cosignatory is a person who can vote for

some resolution.

Participation: Developed UI components

Worked with multiple application data flow

Used react-hook-form

Handled CRUD operations on the frontend side

Technologies: React, Next.js, CSS Modules

Tools: VS Code, Slak, Gitlab, Swagger, Figma, Jira

Corporate Website and Blog System for PixelPlex

Role: Frontend developer at PixelPlex

Participation: Transferred application from Vue.js to React.js

Used AMP framework for blog pages

Performed base structure of styles and UI components architecture

Performed an adaptation of the service to mobile devices

Handled CRUD operations on the frontend side

Integrated accessibility HTML standards

Technologies: React, Vue, Next.js, CSS Modules

Tools: WordPress, VS Code, Slak, PageSpeed Insights, Gitlab, AMP, Figma, Jira

Echo

Role: Frontend developer at PixelPlex

Description: Echo is a blockchain application development platform and network

powered by the integration of Bitcoin and smart contracts. The platform enables efficient decentralized applications for Bitcoin and Ethereum with advanced functionality, flexibility, and usability. The Echo project includes a

lot of services inside.

Participation: Developed desktop crypto wallets: Blip, EchoWallet

Developed Metamask like browser extension crypto wallet - Bridge

Developed Echo Explorer - Echo block explorer with visualizations of current state and transaction history through graphs, charts, and tables.

Technologies: React, ElectronJS, Redux

Tools: Jira, Slack, Figma, VSCode, Gitlab, Swagger

Education

Belarusian State University
Bachelor`s degree, faculty of social and cultural communications
Cultural studies (2011 - 2016)